A Guide to the Rockefeller Family papers, Home Movies and Newsreels FA1303
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Newsreels, 1924 - 1971; 6; 56 film reels
  - Mme Chiang Kai-Shek Asks World of Free Men After the War, 1943; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11689)
    Movietone News. Madam Chiang Kai-Shek United Nations speech, with John D. Rockefeller Jr. in attendance.
  - This Is America — Rockefeller Center, 1944; 35mm film (Reel AV 11674)
    RKO Radio Pictures. Rockefeller Center: This Is America, July 28 1944. (II, 10)
    This film provides a detailed guided tour through the recently-completed complex. From the outside to the inside, from street-level to observation deck, from machines far below the street to a cocktail bar in the top floor, the cameras move through the buildings. Viewers are made acquainted with the high-speed elevators, with the crowds of tourists and guided tours, with the rooftop gardens, and with such technical services as the restaurants, air conditioning plants, window and floor cleaning operations, locksmith shops, and the post office.
    A comparatively long sequence introduces the Radio City Music Hall: on view are the dancing Rockettes at leisure, at practice on the roof, and on the stage of the Music Hall. Special attention is given to the backstage activities, including scene design, choreography, rehearsal, and technical aspects of production. Similarly, on a tour of the NBC radio broadcasting facilities, viewers are taken "backstage" to see the technicians, actors, sound effects men, announcers, orchestras, and control rooms. In the experimental television studios, the relatively unfamiliar invention is introduced as "radio with eyes."
  - Greater New York Fund Appeal Made by Mayor O'Dwyer, circa 1948; Sound, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 11658)
    Movietone News. New York Fund Charity Appeal with John D. Rockefeller Jr., Mayor William O'Dwyer, and Cardinal Spellman.
  - Signing Construction Contract for United Nations Headquarters, 1949; 35mm film; Silent, Black and white, 1 minute (Reel AV 11690)
    Signing the construction contract for the United Nations headquarters, January 28, 1949, with Secretary General Trygve Lie, Lou R. Crandall, and Wallace K. Harrison. Unknown movie studio. Soundtrack missing.
  - Jackie at Opening of 1st Unit of N.Y.C. Cultural Center, 1962; 35mm film; Sound, Black and white, 2 minutes (Reel AV 11691)
    Movietone News. Opening of Philharmonic Hall in New York City, September 23, 1962. Jacqueline Kennedy is accompanied by John D. Rockefeller 3rd. Also in attendance: Nelson A. Rockefeller; New York City Mayor Robert F. Wagner; U Thant, United Nations Acting Secretary General; Adlai Stevenson, U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations, Senator Jacob Javits; and Dean Rusk, U.S. Secretary of State.
  - Dedication of Greenacre Park, 1971; Sound, Color, 1 minute (Reel AV 11692)
    WNBC-TV. Greenacre Park opening, October 14, 1971. In attendance: Abby "Babs" Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, and Happy Rockefeller.